<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Lambda]]></title>
  <link href="http://getlambda.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://getlambda.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-29T16:28:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://getlambda.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lambda]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For The Love Of Freelance - The Top 5 Reasons A Great Freelance Developer Makes Great Business Sense]]></title>
    <link href="http://getlambda.com/2013/10/25/for-the-love-of-freelance.html"/>
    <updated>2013-10-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://getlambda.com/2013/10/25/for-the-love-of-freelance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like any entrepreneur, freelance developers are passionate about what they do. They know their industry. And they’re driven to be the best. Having a short burst of this kind a player on your team could be exactly what your business needs. Here are the top 5 reasons why:</p>

<!--more-->

<h1>1 Freelancers Are Good For Your Bottom Line</h1>

<p>Freelance developers may charge higher hourly or day rates, but in the end they can save you money when you remember that a higher rate buys you quality and efficiency. By choosing freelance you are choosing an extremely skilled candidate whose ability to deliver higher quality work fast actually maximizes your savings and improves productivity to boot.</p>

<p>You also save on overhead. With freelance, you don’t pay for vacations, health insurance or other HR benefits. Depending on the contract, you may not have to pay taxes. Freelance costs may even be considered a deductible business expense. Plus, since their work is their passion, freelancers will arrive at your project with the best software and top-of-the-line equipment.</p>

<h1>2 Freelancers Are Flexible</h1>

<p>With freelance developers, you only pay for the time you need. So when your workflow goes up, you can bring in a resource. When it goes down, you can let that resource go.</p>

<p>No single developer is great at every type of work. So when a specific project comes in with a particular skill set, you can hire a developer who’s the best to fit for that need.</p>

<h1>3 Freelancers Want to Be Freelancers</h1>

<p>For a lot of developers, being freelance is a choice. They are not in between jobs. They are not looking for a permanent gig. They are great at what they do and this is the way they want to do it.</p>

<p>Freelancer developers don’t want to stay on at your business forever -- they like new challenges in new places. They’re interested in coming in for the surgical strike and then moving on. Most likely they have their next assignment lined up. And, the truth is, if they wanted to work on staff, they would be working on staff.</p>

<h1>4 Freelancers are Experienced Professionals</h1>

<p>By hiring from a freelance pool you have the opportunity to get the best talent for your job. In fact, you can pick a developer whose experience and passion matches your project or industry. If freelance developers weren’t great at what they did, they wouldn’t be getting the right work or the right rate. And you can be pretty certain that they will be dedicated to delivering the same excellence to you that they delivered on their last assignment. That’s because...</p>

<h1>5 Freelancers Bank On Their Reputation. Literally.</h1>

<p>Freelancers know that their next job depends on hitting their current assignment out of the park. The success of their business comes from their personal network based on successful projects and engagements. They need to put your business success in their portfolio. And they know, that nobody will rehire or even recommend a mediocre resource.  </p>

<p>In a nutshell, a freelance developer, who’s worth his or her rate, will come in, do your work and then happily get off your payroll -- that’s a business solution you won’t want to pass up.</p>

<p>What do you think? Do you have any tales of freelance success?  Send us an email and let us know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
