<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Lambda]]></title>
  <link href="http://getlambda.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://getlambda.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-14T10:50:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://getlambda.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lambda]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Work. Succeed. Repeat: How to Get Hired Over and Over Again.]]></title>
    <link href="http://getlambda.com/2013/11/05/how-to-get-hired-over-and-over-again.html"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://getlambda.com/2013/11/05/how-to-get-hired-over-and-over-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your incredible talent will get you in the door.  But even if you do the most amazing job, if you come with drama and complications you won’t be asked back.  Here are a few pointers to help make sure you get called in every time.</p>

<!--more-->

<h2>Exceed expectations</h2>

<p>If the client hired you, it’s likely they are working over capacity. That means they have less time to do more work, including overseeing your project.  So be professional at all aspects of the job.  Get to meetings on time.  Meet deadlines. And try to accommodate their schedule as best you can.</p>

<h2>Stick to the Task at Hand</h2>

<p>You may have been recommended for your creative thinking, but in the end they hired you to do the job they have already delineated.  If you have a great new idea, by all means, suggest it, but make sure you have the brief covered.  The client will appreciate your fresh perspective only if they feel you have their main assignment covered.</p>

<h2>Listen Before You Talk</h2>

<p>This sounds like a no brainer, but a lot of freelancers don’t get rehired because they get the reputation of being difficult. So serve up your great solution, but only after you’ve carefully listened to the client feedback.  If the client has to spend a lot of time struggling to make you understand their point, they won’t remember you as a thought leader, they’ll remember you as a pain.</p>

<h2>Be Discreet</h2>

<p>Your current client is paying your for your skills and expertise.  And while, your last job may inform your current work, remember to be appropriate when you share ideas that came for a previous client’s project. You don’t want anyone to think you will be giving away their strategic thinking, capabilities, or proprietary work.</p>

<h2>Check In Along the Project</h2>

<p>Until a client trusts you know what you’re doing you may want to set up mini check in. That way you can show them you are on track, and it also gives you both a good idea if the hours you originally agreed on are accurate.</p>

<h2>Don’t Pad Your Hours</h2>

<p>Be sensitive to the client’s scope. But don’t sell yourself short. If you feel like you need more time than you originally estimated, let the client know early on, so they can make the decision if they can afford (or want) to change their budget.</p>

<h2>Be On Their Radar</h2>

<p>Once you’ve finished up, check in and let your client know that you are available again. Reinforce your latest gigs so that they remember that you are in high demand. If they don’t respond to one email, follow up&mdash;emails do get lost&mdash;but don’t bombard them. This where social media can help.  If you are connected with them on LinkedIn or follow them on Twitter, you’ll have a more consistent presence organically and they’ll be able to see what you’re up to.</p>

<h2>Be The Solution</h2>

<p>Finally, be great at what they asked you to do. Come in with the skills and the knowledge to get the job done. Do it on time, within budget, and better than they expected.  Your job is to make your client look good. If you do that, they’ll remember it and give you another call the next time they need help.</p>

<p>What do you think? How do you make your clients love you (and call again)?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For The Love Of Freelance - The Top 5 Reasons A Great Freelance Developer Makes Great Business Sense]]></title>
    <link href="http://getlambda.com/2013/10/25/for-the-love-of-freelance.html"/>
    <updated>2013-10-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://getlambda.com/2013/10/25/for-the-love-of-freelance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like any entrepreneur, freelance developers are passionate about what they do. They know their industry. And they’re driven to be the best. Having a short burst of this kind of player on your team could be exactly what your business needs. Here are the top 5 reasons why:</p>

<!--more-->

<h1>1 Freelancers Are Good For Your Bottom Line</h1>

<p>Freelance developers may charge higher hourly or day rates, but in the end they can save you money when you remember that a higher rate buys you quality and efficiency. By choosing freelance you are choosing an extremely skilled candidate whose ability to deliver higher quality work fast actually maximizes your savings and improves productivity to boot.</p>

<p>You also save on overhead. With freelance, you don’t pay for vacations, health insurance or other HR benefits. Depending on the contract, you may not have to pay taxes. Freelance costs may even be considered a deductible business expense. Plus, since their work is their passion, freelancers will arrive at your project with the best software and top-of-the-line equipment.</p>

<h1>2 Freelancers Are Flexible</h1>

<p>With freelance developers, you only pay for the time you need. So when your workflow goes up, you can bring in a resource. When it goes down, you can let that resource go.</p>

<p>No single developer is great at every type of work. So when a specific project comes in with a particular skill set, you can hire a developer who’s the best to fit for that need.</p>

<h1>3 Freelancers Want to Be Freelancers</h1>

<p>For a lot of developers, being freelance is a choice. They are not in between jobs. They are not looking for a permanent gig. They are great at what they do and this is the way they want to do it.</p>

<p>Freelancer developers don’t want to stay on at your business forever -- they like new challenges in new places. They’re interested in coming in for the surgical strike and then moving on. Most likely they have their next assignment lined up. And, the truth is, if they wanted to work on staff, they would be working on staff.</p>

<h1>4 Freelancers are Experienced Professionals</h1>

<p>By hiring from a freelance pool you have the opportunity to get the best talent for your job. In fact, you can pick a developer whose experience and passion matches your project or industry. If freelance developers weren’t great at what they did, they wouldn’t be getting the right work or the right rate. And you can be pretty certain that they will be dedicated to delivering the same excellence to you that they delivered on their last assignment. That’s because...</p>

<h1>5 Freelancers Bank On Their Reputation. Literally.</h1>

<p>Freelancers know that their next job depends on hitting their current assignment out of the park. The success of their business comes from their personal network based on successful projects and engagements. They need to put your business success in their portfolio. And they know, that nobody will rehire or even recommend a mediocre resource.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, a freelance developer, who’s worth his or her rate, will come in, do your work and then happily get off your payroll -- that’s a business solution you won’t want to pass up.</p>

<p>What do you think? Do you have any tales of freelance success?  Send us an email and let us know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
